gsapubs.org 2018-11-06

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

GeoScienceWorld is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. As an end-user, should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. This Privacy Policy provides an explanation as to what happens to any personal data that you provide to us, or that we collect from you.

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of information as outlined below. We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. If such an event occurs we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are informed of and content with any changes.

**Legal Basis**

GeoScienceWorld is collecting and processing individual personal data for the legitimate interests of GeoScienceWorld, including the proper administration of this website, customer service, and promotion of GeoScienceWorld offerings. 

**Information We Collect**

Details of your visits to our website and the resources that you access, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data.

Information that you provide by registering for an account on the GeoScienceWorld portal (name, email address), or by filling in forms on our website, such as when you signup to receive email alerts or register for personalization options on the GeoScienceWorld portal.

Information provided to us when you communicate with us for any reason, including submitting a question or request through the feedback/contact us form on our site.

**Specific to the GeoScienceWorld Portal**

While using the GeoScienceWorld portal website, you can opt to establish a customized account that requires the input of account information (name, email address and password) and personalization preferences (email alerts). We do not gather financial or demographic information. We maintain this information in strict privacy and do not share it with others except in the form of grouped statistics. None of the shared data is personally identifiable. You can update or delete your account and preference choices at any time. In the case of our alerting services, the e-mail addresses and names of users who elect to be alerted about content in selected publications are sent to the publishers of those publications; GeoScienceWorld-affiliated publishers may use this information for marketing purposes.

GeoScienceWorld automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including information such as the name of the domain and host from which you are accessing the Internet (for example, aol.com or stanford.edu); the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer; the type of browser software you are using; and the pages you request for viewing. This information is used to understand how our site is being used. GeoScienceWorld does not use this information to individually identify specific users and your activity on our site. Aggregated reports on overall site usage are developed and shared with GeoScienceWorld-affiliated publishers, but individuals and their specific usage details are never personally identified.

As part of the registration process, you have the option to allow your name and email address to be supplied to GeoScienceWorld-affiliated publishers to receive email information about their associations and publications. You can decide to accept or decline this option during the registration process or at any time by selecting modify my personal information.

**Use of Cookies**

On occasion, we may gather information about your computer for our services and to provide statistical information regarding the use of our website to our publishing partners. Such information will not identify you personally, it is just statistical data about our visitors and their use of our site. These statistical data do not identify any personal details whatsoever.

Similarly to the above, we may gather information about your general Internet use by using a cookie file. A cookie is a small file, which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

All computers have the ability to automatically accept or decline cookies. This can be done by activating the setting on your browser, which determines how to deal with cookies. Please note that should you choose to decline cookies, you may be unable to access particular parts of our website.

GeoScienceWorld does not use cookies to track what other sites you have visited. Cookies are a required feature to support the personalization features within the GeoScienceWorld site. You can still use our site without cookies being involved as long as you do not register, sign in, or use the personalization features.

GeoScienceWorld does not look at or track any personal or confidential information about our users. Cookies created while visiting the GeoScienceWorld site are deleted when you click "Sign Out". If you do not sign out, then the cookies will remain until you quit your browser.

**Use of Your Information**

GeoScienceWorld respects your privacy. We do not sell, exchange, or release your personal information (name, email address) without your consent, regardless of its source, to any third parties. The information that we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provide services to you.

Please be advised that we do not reveal information about identifiable individuals to GeoScienceWorld-affiliated publishers but we may, on occasion, provide them with aggregate statistical information about our visitors, compiled from registration data and log file data. In addition, if you provide your e-mail address and contact name to set up alerts on a particular publishers' site, they will be able to access that information, as outlined below.

**Storing Your Personal Data**

Data that is provided to us is stored on our secure servers. Details relating to any transactions entered into on our site will be encrypted to enhance its safety. The transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of data sent to us electronically and transmission of such data is therefore entirely at your own risk. Further, we cannot guarantee that information stored on our system or otherwise in our care will be immune from unintended release or unauthorized intrusion. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password so that you can access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

**Access to Personal Data**

An individual who wishes to access, correct, or delete their personal data should direct their inquiry to GeoScienceWorld as provided under “Contact Us,” below.

**Retention of Personal Data**

We will retain personal data that we process for as long as needed to provide our services and otherwise serve the legitimate interests of GeoScienceWorld.

**Site of Processing of Personal Data** Personal data of individuals collected by GeoScienceWorld may be stored and processed in the United States, Europe, or any other country in which GeoScienceWorld, its vendors, or partners maintain facilities. GeoScienceWorld may transfer personal data for processing across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world.

**Ecommerce Transactions**

Ecommerce transactions on our sites are managed by 3rd party transaction providers, such as PayPal and its affiliates. Credit card or account numbers are not visible to GeoScienceWorld employees.

**Disclosing Your Information**

Where applicable, we may disclose your login information to members of our staff. We may also disclose the personal information you voluntarily provide if/when legally required and/or to assist fraud protection and minimize credit risk

**Third Party Links**

You might find links to third party websites on our site. These websites should have their own privacy policies, which you should check. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies whatsoever as we have no control over them.

**Exceptions for Library Administration, Pricing Quotes, Troubleshooting, and Piracy Protection**

As a nonprofit collaborative organization, we share some customer data with our participating publishers and governing bodies. Typically, customer-level information may be shared in order to: a) generate price quotes; b) report business results; c) calculate content royalties; c) troubleshoot technical issues; or d) investigate issues having to do with usage or suspected piracy or misuse of content. Because we employ third-party technology partners, we may also share information with technology vendors in order to support technology services, resolve technical issues, or investigate issues relating to data reporting or suspected misuse of content. If misuse of content occurs from a specific library access point, we will share data with the library staff at that location.

**Contacting Us**

We welcome any queries, comments or requests you may have regarding this Privacy Policy. Please do not hesitate to [send us feedback](https://pubs.geoscienceworld.org/contact-us).
